Guide to the Time Inc. Magazine Development Group Records 1967-1987, 2003 MS 3009-RG 40
New-York Historical Society
- Series I.B.4.a. 1973 to 1978 Business and Publishing: General Manager Winston Cox Files, 1971-1975; 3,25 Linear feet in 4 record cartons
  - Subseries I.B.4.a.iii. Magazines, 1971-1975
    - People: Advertising: Swaps, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 27)
    - People: Advertising: Trade Promotion, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 28)
    - People: Canada, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 29)
    - People: Circulation, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 30)
    - People: Circulation: Controlled Circulation, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 31)
    - People: Circulation: Crash Month, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 32)
    - People: Circulation: Planning, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 33)
    - People: Circulation: Planning: Consumer Promotion, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 34)
    - People: Circulation: Planning: Field Force, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 35)
    - People: Circulation: Planning: Price Testing, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 36)
    - People: Circulation: Planning: Racking, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 37)
    - People: Circulation: Planning: Ranking Meeting, 1974 June 11 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 38)
    - People: Circulation: Planning: Reallocations, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 39)
    - People: Circulation: Planning: Trade Promotion, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 40)
    - People: Circulation: Promotion, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 41)
    - People: Corporate Circulation Monthly Report, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 42)
    - People: Editorial, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 43)
    - People: Edit Mockups by Issue, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 44)
    - People: Edit Research, 1974 (Offsite-box 3724, Folder 45)
    - People: Letter Totals, 1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 1)
    - People: Meeting, 1974 May 22 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 2)
    - People: Monthly Report, 1974 November (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 3)
    - People: Newsstand Circulation, 1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 4)
    - People: Passalong Readership, 1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 5)
    - People: Promotion, 1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 6)
    - People: Production, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 7)
    - People: Production: Edit Closings, 1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 8)
    - People: Production: John Gallagher to Discuss, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 9)
    - People: Publicity Personnel, 1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 10)
    - People: Research, 1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 11)
    - People: Research: Trendex: Awareness [empty], circa 1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 12)
    - People: Research: Levis Organization: The Marketing of Magazines in Supermarkets, 1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 13)
    - People: Research: Simmons Audience Data, 1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 14)
    - People: Sales Estimates, 1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 15)
    - People: Weekly Reports and Other Updates, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 16)
    - View: Prototypes?, 1973 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 17)
    - Well and Money (George Wiedemann materials), 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 18)
- Series I.B.4.b. 1973 to 1978 Business and Publishing: General Managers Winston Cox and Deane Raley Files, 1970-1977; 3.25 Linear feet in 5 record cartons
  Winston "Tony" Cox was an original member of the new Magazine Development Group holding the role of General Manager from 1973 to 1976. At that time, Deane Raley took over as GM. Prior to 1976, Raley was a production manager in the Time Inc. Production Department as well as an assistant to Group Vice President in charge of Magazine Publishing Art Keylor.
  This subseries contains Winston Cox's and Deane Raley's files that were found mixed together, maybe due to the transition of the role of General Manager from Cox to Raley. The files have not been separated.
  Records document the business and publishing decisions made by the Magazines Development Group.
  Restricted material includes staff performance reviews and agreements or contracts with Time Inc. as a party.
  Organized into four subseries:
  Subseries I.B.3.a. Administrative Files
  Subseries I.B.3.b. Money
  Subseries I.B.3.c. New Magazine Ideas
  Subseries I.B.3.d. People
  - Subseries I.B.4.b.i. Administrative Files, 1973-1977; 0.75 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
    Administrative Files document business and publishing administrative activities and decisions of the Magazine Development Group.
    - Act Media, 1977 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 19)
    - Annual Reports from Other Companies, 1977 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 20)
    - Budgets, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 21)
    - Expenses of Attending Foreign Conventions, 1977 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 22)
    - General Electric / Time Inc., 1977 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 23)
    - How and Why People Buy Magazines, 1976 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 24)
    - Ideas on Launching a New Magazine, 1973 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 25)
    - Magazine Publishers Financial Reports, 1976 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 26)
    - Magazine Readership Study, 1975 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 27)
    - Magazine Single-Copy Sales, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 28)
    - Magazine Startups, 1977 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 29)
    - Media Network, Inc., 1976 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 30)
    - Mergers, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 31-32)
    - New York Subways Ads, 1976 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 33)
    - Non Paid Filler Ads, 1974 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 34)
    - Overhead Costs to Magazines, 1977 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 35)
    - Personnel, 1974-1977 (Offsite-box 3725, Folder 36)
    - Personnel [RESTRICTED], 1974-1977 (Offsite-box R68)
    - Reader's Digest Merchandising Allowance, 1975 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 1)
    - Research: List of Mail Research Projects, 1976 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 2)
    - Salaries / Bonuses, 1974-1977 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 3)
    - Select Magazines Distribution, 1974 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 4)
    - Stanford Court Hotel, 1974 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 5)
    - Simmons, 1977 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 6)
    - Strategic Planning: Forecast, 1974 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 7)
    - Time Inc. Media Seminar, 1977 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 8)
    - Videocomp: Airey, Norm, 1977 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 9)
  - Subseries I.B.4.b.ii. Money, 1973-1974; 0.2 Linear feet in 2 folders
    Money includes financial planning records for the early years of the publication.
    - Budgets, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 10)
    - Strategic Planning, 1973 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 11)
  - Subseries I.B.4.b.iii. New Magazine Ideas, 1970-1976; 0.75 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    New Magazine Ideas include charts listing ideas and the status of the idea, such as "no interest" or "under discussion"; and correspondence and proposals with suggestions for new magazines.
    There is one folder of 1970 material from Stevens DeClerque, Assistant Publisher of Life.
    Organized alphabetically with general files in chronological order at the front.
    - General, 1973 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 12)
    - General, 1974 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 13-16)
    - General, 1975 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 17-18)
    - General, 1976 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 19)
    - Everyday, 1974 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 20)
    - Hillsboro Associates, 1976 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 21)
    - Lifetime Sports, 1976 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 22)
    - Lime House, 1976 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 23)
    - Mind and Body, circa 1975 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 24)
    - Outlook, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 25)
    - Saving and Spending, 1976 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 26)
    - Sunlight, 1976 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 27)
    - TV Plus, 1970 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 28)
    - World Legal Letter, 1976 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 29)
  - Subseries I.B.4.b.iv. People, 1973-1977; 1.95 Linear feet in 4 record cartons
    The files on People document business decisions for the first few years of publication, particularly advertising. Records include weekly reports from People Publisher Dick Durrell to Group Vice President in charge of Magazine Publishing Art Keylor regarding activities in editorial, circulation, advertising, promotion and publicity.
    - Advertising, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 30-31)
    - Advertising: Consumer, 1974 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 32)
    - Advertising: Gatefold Pricing, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 33)
    - Advertising: Marketing Organization, 1975 (Offsite-box 3726, Folder 34)
    - Advertising: Monthly Report, 1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 1)
    - Advertising: Pricing, 1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 2)
    - Advertising: Production Problems, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 3)
    - Advertising: Promotion, 1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 4)
    - Advertising: Quality Issues, 1977 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 5)
    - Advertising: Rates, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 6-7)
    - Advertising: Report by Issue, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 8-9)
    - Advertising: Research, 1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 10)
    - Advertising: Sales Travel and Entertainment Report, 1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 11)
    - Advertising: Swaps, 1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 12)
    - Associated Press Contract, 1976 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 13)
    - Awareness Study, 1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 14)
    - Bonus Plan, 1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 15)
    - Broadcast Swapping, 1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 16)
    - Bulk Copies, 1974 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 17)
    - Chain Distribution, 1974 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 18)
    - Checkpoints, 1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 19)
    - Circulation, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 20-22)
    - Circulation: ABC Reports, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 23)
    - Circulation: Monthly Report, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 24)
    - Circulation: Promotion, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 25)
    - Circulation: Trade Promotion, 1974 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 26)
    - Cole Monger Waterhouse, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 27)
    - Cole Monger Waterhouse [RESTRICTED], 1974-1975 (Offsite-box R68)
    - Complimentary List, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 28)
    - Covers, 1976 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 29)
    - Delivery, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 30)
    - Deliveries: Late, 1977 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 31)
    - Distribution, 1974 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 32)
    - Ditton, Peter, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 33)
    - Edit, 1977 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 34)
    - Edit Closings, 1973-1976 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 35)
    - Field Organization, 1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 36)
    - Filler Space, 1976 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 37)
    - Food Chains, 1974 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 38-39)
    - Fulfillment, 1973 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 40)
    - Grunwald, Henry, 1974 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 41)
    - Legal, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 42-43)
    - Letters, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 44)
    - Newsletters, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 45)
    - Newsstand, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 46-47)
    - Permissions, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 48-49)
    - PIB Reports, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3727, Folder 50-51)
    - Pictures, 1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 1)
    - Positioning, 1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 2)
    - Postal Rates, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 3)
    - Poster Foldut, 1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 4)
    - Price Testing, 1973-1977 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 5-6)
    - Production, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 7)
    - Profitability, 1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 8)
    - Promotion, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 9-10)
    - Promotion Expenses, 1977 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 11)
    - Promotion: Mailings, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 12)
    - Promotion: Media, 1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 13)
    - Public Place Distribution, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 14-15)
    - Rate Card, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 16)
    - Reprints, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 17)
    - Research, 1977 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 18)
    - Retail Display Program, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 19)
    - Sales: Field Force, 1974 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 20)
    - Sales: Meeting: Bermuda, 1977 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 21)
    - Sales: Weekly Sales Report, 1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 22)
    - Strategic Planning: 18-Month Forecast Review, 1974 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 23)
    - Subscriber Delivery Report, 1977 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 24)
    - Subscriptions, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 25)
    - Syndication, 1974 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 26-27)
    - Television, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 28-29)
    - Test Markets, 1974 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 30)
    - Time Distribution Services: Bonus Plan, 1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 31)
    - Time Distribution Services: Meeting, 1975 July 7 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 32)
    - Time Distribution Services: Memoranda, 1976 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 33)
    - UPC Identification, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 34)
    - Us (magazine), 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 35)
    - Videocomp, 1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 36)
    - Weekly Reports, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 37-41)
    - Wholesaler Allocations / Traffic and Distribution, 1973 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 42)
    - Wholesaler Incentive Plan, 1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 43)
    - Wholesaler Incentive Program, 1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 44)
    - Year End Issue, 1975 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 45)
- Series I.B.4.c. 1973 to 1978 Business and Publishing: General Manager Deane Raley Files, 1974-1977; 0.4 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
  Deane Raley's files document the exploration into registering People in other countries and finding local publishers to produce it since the distribution of the U.S. edition was very expensive. Includes research into the marketing of, demand for, and circulation of People in other countries.
  Also are two files documenting development of the the women's magazine.
  Restricted material includes agreements or contracts with Time Inc. as a party and staff records with personally indentifiable information.
  - People International: General, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 46)
  - People International: Australia, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 47)
  - People International: Editorial America (Latin America), 1977 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 48-50)
  - People International: Editorial America (Latin America) [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R68)
  - People International: England / France / Germany, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 51-52)
  - People International: England / France / Germany [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Offsite-box R68)
  - People International: Japan, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3728, Folder 53)
  - People International: Picture Rights and Contracts, 1976 (Offsite-box 3729, Folder 1)
  - People International: Picture Rights and Contracts, 1976 (Offsite-box R68)
  - Women's Magazine: Budgets, 1977 (Offsite-box 3729, Folder 2)
  - Women's Magazine: Personnel, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3729, Folder 3)
  - Women's Magazine: Personnel [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Offsite-box R68)
- Series I.B.5. 1973 to 1978 Business and Publishing: Business Manager Paul Hale Files, 1969-1978; 6.3 Linear feet in 8 record cartons
  Paul Hale was the Money Business Manager from 1972 to 1973, and the Magazine Development Group (MDG) Business Manager from 1974 to 1977. When the MDG closed in 1978, he became the People Business Manager.
  Paul Hale's files document the business and publishing decisions made by the Magazines Development Group, particularly reader letters during the first year of People, and the business decisions, strategic planning and weekly reporting specific to People and Money, and Life Special Reports.
  Organized into seven subseries:
  Subseries I.B.5.a. General Administrative Files
  Subseries I.B.5.b. Magazine Development Administrative Files
  Subseries I.B.5.c. Letters Department
  Subseries I.B.4.d. Life Special Reports
  Subseries I.B.5.e. Money
  Subseries I.B.5.f. People
  Subseries I.B.5.g. Women's Magazine
  Series were determined by the archivist.
  - Subseries I.B.5.a. General Administrative Files, 1969-1978; 1 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
    General Administrative Files contains records regarding activities and duties not specifically related to the Magazine Development Group (MDG) including Hale's expense reports that predate the MDG and memoranda sent out by Time Inc. corporate to all staff at Time Inc.
    - Accounts Payable Procedures, 1974 (Offsite-box 3729, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 3729, Folder 5-6)
    - Automotive Strike Policy, 1976 (Offsite-box 3729, Folder 7)
    - Daily Telephone Messages, 1975 (Offsite-box 3729, Folder 8-9)
    - Expense Reports, 1969-1974 (Offsite-box 3729, Folder 10-11)
    - Folio: Conference: Legal and Business Problems of the Magazine Publishing Industry, 1977 (Offsite-box 3729, Folder 12)
    - Folio: New Magazine Report, 1975 (Offsite-box 3729, Folder 13)
    - Folio: Seminars and Workshops, 1974-1977 (Offsite-box 3729, Folder 14-15)
    - The Gallagher Report, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3729, Folder 16-18)
    - Media Curriculum Seminar: Time Inc. Media Update Session, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3729, Folder 19-21)
    - Media Curriculum Seminar: Time Inc. Media Update Session, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3730, Folder 1)
    - Memoranda to the Staff, 1972-1975 (Offsite-box 3730, Folder 2-3)
    - Vacations, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 3730, Folder 4-5)
  - Subseries I.B.5.b. Magazine Development Administrative Files, 1972-1978; 2 Linear feet in 4 record cartons
    Magazine Development Administrative Files document administrative activities and decisions of the Magazine Development Group (MDG) including registering the copyright for the magazines handled by the MDG; questions about translated articles from Money in the Japanese President magazine; creation of the Letters Department within the MDG; strategic planning for the MDG; and weekly reports on the activities of the MDG sent to Group Vice President in charge of Magazine Publication Arthur Keylor and later to MDG Director Garry Valk.
    Restricted material include agreements or contracts with Time Inc. as a party.
    Organized alphabetically with general materials at the front.
    - General, 1972-1977 (Offsite-box 3730, Folder 6-11)
    - Accounting, 1973 (Offsite-box 3730, Folder 12)
    - Acquisition Possibilities, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3730, Folder 13-14)
    - Advertising?: Billing, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 3730, Folder 15)
    - Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3730, Folder 16)
    - Budget, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3730, Folder 17-18)
    - Closings, 1972 (Offsite-box 3730, Folder 19)
    - Complimentary / Promotion List, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3730, Folder 20)
    - Copyright Claim Registration: Money, 1972-1975 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 1)
    - Copyright Claim Registration: People, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 2)
    - Development Meeting, 1976 October 28 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 3)
    - Fawcett Publications, Inc., 1976 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 4)
    - Feature Magazine Proposal from Austin Furst, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 5)
    - The Future of Magazines Study, 1975 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 6-7)
    - Housing, 1977 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 8)
    - Letters Department Organization, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 9-10)
    - Life Monthlies, 1974 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 11)
    - Life Monthly (New), 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 12)
    - New Ideas: Man's Day, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 13)
    - News Service Fee, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 14)
    - Organization (MDG), 1973-1976 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 15)
    - President / Diamond-Time, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 16-17)
    - President / Diamond-Time [RESTRICTED], 1973-1974 (Offsite-box R68)
    - Service Allocation Study, 1977 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 18)
    - Spin-Offs, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 19)
    - Staff Headcount, 1975-1977 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 20)
    - Strategic Planning: Special Budget Studies, 1971-1973 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 21-22)
    - Strategic Planning: Forecast, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 23)
    - Strategic Planning: 1975 Two-Year Plan, 1972-1975 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 24-26)
    - Strategic Planning: Five-Year Plan, 1976 (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 27)
    - Strategic Planning: 1976 Two-Year Plan Revised (Offsite-box 3731, Folder 28)
    - Strategic Planning: 1976 Two-Year Plan (Offsite-box 3732, Folder 1-2)
    - Strategic Planning: General, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3732, Folder 3)
    - Ventures: Outside Possibilities, 1972-1976 (Offsite-box 3732, Folder 4-5)
    - Weekly Reports, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 3732, Folder 6-8)
  - Subseries I.B.5.c. Letters Department, 1974; 0.2 Linear feet in 3 folders
    Letters Department includes letters sent in by readers of People magazine during its first year of publication requesting prints of photographs, questions about celebrity trivia, and containing letters to forward on to people featured in the articles. Time Inc. declined to forward any letters.
    - General, 1974 (Offsite-box 3732, Folder 9-10)
    - Special Replies, 1974 (Offsite-box 3732, Folder 11)
  - Subseries I.B.4.d. Life Special Reports, 1973-1977; 1 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
    Life Special Reports were published twice a year by former Life staff within the Magazine Development Group after the closure of the weekly Life and are a continuation of the Life special issues.
    Life Special Reports contains records on the business decisions and publication of these biannually published issues. Records discuss cover testing, pricing, production, distribution, advertising sales, publicity packets of news collected by Corporate Public Affairs including television and radio appearance transcripts; and itemizations of spending.
    Restricted material includes staff payments with personally identifying information.
    Organized chronologically by issue published with general files at the end.
    - 1973: The Spirit of Israel, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3732, Folder 12)
    - 1974: The Year in Pictures 1973 (Offsite-box 3732, Folder 13)
    - 1974: General (Offsite-box 3732, Folder 14)
    - 1974: Operating Statements (Offsite-box 3732, Folder 15)
    - 1974: One Day in the Life of America (Offsite-box 3732, Folder 16)
    - 1975: Year in Pictures (1974) (Offsite-box 3732, Folder 17)
    - 1975: General (Offsite-box 3732, Folder 18)
    - 1975: Bicentennial Issue: The 100 Events That Shaped America, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3733, Folder 1-6)
    - 1975: Bicentennial Issue: The 100 Events That Shaped America [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R68)
    - 1976: Year in Pictures (1975) (Offsite-box 3733, Folder 7-8)
    - 1976: Remarkable American Women (Offsite-box 3733, Folder 9-12)
    - General: Miscellaneous, 1977 (Offsite-box 3733, Folder 13)
    - General: Joseph W. Foraker Learning Programs, 1976 (Offsite-box 3733, Folder 14)
    - General: Single Copy Orders, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3733, Folder 15)
    - General: 200 Great Photos, 1976 (Offsite-box 3733, Folder 16)
  - Subseries I.B.5.e. Money, 1971-1976; 0.3 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
    Includes Paul Hale's files on Money from when he was Money Business Manager and the Magazine Development Group Business Manager.
    - Budget, 1972 (Offsite-box 3733, Folder 17)
    - Other Magazines, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3733, Folder 18)
    - Production, 1972 (Offsite-box 3733, Folder 19)
    - Requests for Reprints and Issues, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 3733, Folder 20)
    - Reprints and Permissions, 1972 (Offsite-box 3733, Folder 21-22)
    - Strategic Planning: Two-Year Plan, 1976 (Offsite-box 3734, Folder 1-2)
    - Weekly Reports, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3734, Folder 3)
  - Subseries I.B.5.f. People, 1974-1977; 0.5 Linear feet in 1 record carton